Xiu Zhu(Drew)

+86 156-0165-4544 drew.xiu@gmail.com https://github.com/noru

### **OVERVIEW**

I'm a gamer. The recent games I play are Detroit: Become human & PUBG. I was a serious War3 & DOTA player (from v6.3 - 6.8), MOBA is my genre. It's easy for anyone to say "I'm a gamer" but what does that mean? I would quote <u>Joker's line in <Suicide Squad></u> and say, a gamer not only plays, but also got inspired and lives by the games he love. I hope this piece of <u>fan art I just finished</u> proves me a little bit.

Technical perspective, I have 5 years programming experience in a wide range of technical stacks. Strong learning ability and willingness. Team player and efficient communicator, always took a role as key developer in team. Tech nerd and enthusiastic about efficiency and quality. Full stack web developer since beginning, and now an experienced front-end engineer. Looking forward to sharpen my skills and acquire new ones.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

My <u>Github</u> is me as an engineer in a nutshell. Take the 6 pinned repos as example, I'm not a 10k-start repo maintainer but:

- I document seriously, in English, with working demo.
- I test seriously (~90% if it is non trivial component, e.g. jike-scada, utils)
- I devops seriously (travis is used for auto build/test/publish, life is too short for `sh push.sh`)
- I communicate seriously (all my PR/Issue are addressed properly, mostly within a few days)
- Multilingual, multiple topic (web, mobile, IoT..., although I can only be fluent in one at a time, now JS in web development, last time, Scala in server development)
- Fast learner (I'm a C++ noob, but there is an working CS-GO hack written in C++ which I learnt online.)

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### General Electric; Healthcare Digital China, Front-end Engineer — 2017.4 - now

- Be front-end specialist in Asset Performance Management product team. Lead technical discussion in the team. Influence team member to adopt new tools or establish new working model. e.g.
  - \* arrange regular share sessions.
  - \* introduce testing framework and best practice to the team.
- Data visualization development, such as reports, dashboards. With UX team, implement modern, attractive final UI or reusable components. Not only leverage existing tools (like, D3, echarts), but also create in-house chart solution.
- Constantly evolve the project, not only the front-end side:
  - \* Migrate features from traditional SSR pages to a SPA/micro service architecture.
  - Combine scattered repos, unify technical stack to create a scalable front-end project and improve productivity.
  - \* Integrate & customize 3rd party components like BI tools.
  - \* Establish CI/CD pipeline, and collect data to show the necessity of taking this action.
- Be an early adopter of new techs in the team, learn with actions and spread the result to the other team members. e.g. Use my personal experience performance tuning with immutable data structure to persuade team to adopt such measure in key components of the software; Share my TDD(Test driven

development) experiences in front-end project, list pros and cons, to benefit others in their engineering practice.

- Interviewing front-end engineer for both Shanghai/Beijing team. Keep a open/consistent standard, and timely feedback, to make a better references for others.
- Tech stack: typescript/react + react-\*/antd/echarts

### Autodesk China R&D; Cloud Platform; Software Engineer — 2014.8 - 2017.4

- Working on a RESTful API for Autodesk Revit/Fusion to manage/render materials. Based on asp.net. Built a browser based admin console, using Vuejs.
- Full stack developer of https://apps.autodesk.com. AppStore is a platform built for 3rd party developers or firms to share/sell their plugins. Based on asp.net, with jQuery and angular. Back-end is written in Scala/ Play with MySQL. I'm the sole developer of back-end REST api and involved in most front-end development.

### SAP Labs China; Globalization Service; Developer — 2012.7-2014.8

Developer of ERP Financial modules and their globalized version. Experienced ABAPer and lead team to deliver 3 Fiori(UI5) Apps. ABAP is SAP's own programming language and Fiori(UI5) is an enterprise Html5 framework.

## Autodesk China R&D; Localization Testing; Intern — 2010-2012

Conduct automation testing for Autodesk hero products, develop necessary tools, many of them are using Python. Best Intern Award of 2011.

#### **WORTH-SAYINGS**

Android native apps, Node.js, CICD pipeline(Jenkins, Docker) experience.

## **EDUCATION**

NWPU — Bachelor of Aerodynamics, 2009; Fudan University — Aerodynamics, 2012, completed all courses

# **SKILLS**

OOP, FP, JavaScript stack, React stack, Scala, C#, Android/Java, AWS, Git, REST, SQL, Non-SQL